Powell May

Technology Director + Full-Stack Engineer

Phone: (347) 220-9640

Email: powell.may@gmail.com
GitHub: github.com/ptouch718

Summary

A proven technology leader with over a decade of experience, I have a passion for crafting digital experiences that engage users and support the business of my clients. I believe in leadership by example and aim to foster team environments that promote autonomy, accountability, and personal growth.

Core Competencies

Javascript (ES6), PHP, HTML, CSS, Responsive Web Design, Accessibility, Design Systems, Content Management Systems, Source Control and Deployments, AWS, Linux, REST

Tools, Frameworks and Platforms

Wordpress, Laravel, Gulp, Webpack, Bash/Zsh, Git, SCSS, Vue.js, React, Sketch/Zeplin

Professional Experience

Director of Technology, Sullivan I (June 2018 - Present)

- Along with other digital team leads, helped exceed annual revenue goals and secure numerous digital-first new business relationships.
- Met closely with partner-level leadership to identify key strategic technical goals for the agency.
- Acted as key technical contact for clients, helping plan and support a number of long-term engagements.
- Organized and lead development team planning meetings as well as regular code reviews.

Clients: Two Sigma, Millennium Management, Lord Abbett, Columbia University, Duke University, Yale

University

Technologies: Wordpress, WooCommerce, Drupal, Vue.js, Chart.js, D3.js

Solutions Architect, Sullivan I (February 2016 - June 2018)

- Worked closely with strategic and creative leads to plan and execute digital projects from kick-off to launch.
- Participated heavily in the RFP process with new business teams, providing technical solution proposals, as well as participating in pitch presentations.
- Worked closely with producers and project managers in the creation of scopes and timelines.
- Established repeatable and efficient development processes that produce performant, accessible, and consistent source code.
- Provided consultation and guidance to visual design teams on design systems and component/atomic driven design thinking.
- Lead development teams (internal and external) on the execution of medium and large scale website builds.
- Vetted and established relationships with external recruiters and software development vendors.
- Architected and oversaw the technical implementation for a SPA (single page application) written in Vue.js and a decoupled Drupal 8 backend.
- Architected and developed a large-scale Wordpress multisite platform powering 10+ individual marketing sites.
- Oversaw development of an offline-first mobile sales-enablement tool written in Vue.js and D3.js.

Clients: Two Sigma, Millennium Management, Columbia University, Duke University, Brown University, SAG-AFTRA

Technologies: Wordpress, WooCommerce, Drupal, Vue.js, Chart.js, D3.js

Senior Developer, Sullivan I (March 2011 - February 2016)

- Worked closely with art directors, visual designers, and user experience designers to plan and execute the development of digital projects for a wide range of clients.
- Interfaced with client's IT departments to configure deployment servers for medium to large scale websites and web applications including security intensive financial services environments.
- Implemented content management systems with various technologies including ExpressionEngine, Wordpress, Drupal, Laravel and Django.
- Designed and developed REST APIs for iOS and web applications, as well as configuring scalable environments on Amazon Web Services to run them.
- Provided long-running support and maintenance to clients on all development projects.
- Developed numerous automation, testing and deployment tools for use across all client projects.
- Participated in the hiring and on-boarding of new developers.

Clients: American Express, Charles Schwab, Duke University, Cornell Tech, Brown University, Columbia University, and Baker Tilly.

Technologies: ExpressionEngine, Drupal, Wordpress, REST, Gulp

Front-end Developer, NoFavorite I (December 2006 - March 2011)

- Worked closely with visual designers to develop pixel-prefect responsive front-end code in HTML, CSS and JavaScript from Photoshop documents.
- Developed jQuery plugins for reuse across a various project types and client applications.
- Created front-end boilerplate that included reusable templates and a custom CSS framework.
- Integrated HTML, CSS and JavaScript into a proprietary e-commerce engine and CMS.
- Early adopter of CSS pre-processors (SASS) and emerging JavaScript MV(*) frameworks (Backbone.js)
- Mentored junior developers and promoted development best-practices within the company.

Clients: Sephora, Pepsi, Christo and Jeanne-Claude, Tom Sachs, and Free City.

Technologies: Wordpress, SASS, Backbone.is, Vae platform.

Front-end Developer, Hydra Media Group I (December 2006 - March 2008)

- Participated in the development of a custom LMS (learning management system) and e-commerce for a traffic-management equipment and certification supplier.
- Developed a small e-commerce website in Magento for a local jewelry maker.

Technologies: Code Igniter, Django, Magento, Wordpress, jQuery

Awards

- Webby Associations, SAG-AFTRA Website I (2019)
- Webby Honoree, Columbia Law School Fundraising Campaign Website I (2018)
- Webby 2015 People's Choice, Cornell Tech Website I (2015)
- Awwwards Site of the Day, NoFavorite Website I (2010)

Education

Louisiana State University, Bachelor of Fine Arts I (September 2000 - December 2006)